# Josh Woodcock // Full-Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

**Full-Stack Software Engineer** with over five years of development experience building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies, improving analytics, and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

**Skills:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Google Firebase, MongoDB, Express, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cloud-based Deployment Services (AWS, Heroku, Netlify), Styled Components, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Git, RESTful APIs (Google, Stripe, Twilio), Wordpress, WooCommerce, Photoshop, Illustrator.

### **Experience**

# Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-Present | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Develops front end of brand and artist livestream web apps that provide fans with the ultimate digital music experience.
  Features include event registration, real-time chat, tips / donations via Stripe, and livestream video feed.
- Simplified development and project management process by creating standardized templates for data and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

## **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

General Assembly | July 2020-October 2020 | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Gained hands-on experience working with and utilizing several programming languages and web frameworks, while developing full-stack applications following industry standards and best practices.
- Tech stack used includes React, MongoDB, Express, Node, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

## Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that saw an increase in appointments by over 1000% and helped win two stages of VC funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the booking / scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, Twilio, WooCommerce.

#### MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017–January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Designed and developed corporate website, allowing for easier management and sharing of content utilizing Wordpress.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.

#### **Digital Media Marketing Coordinator**

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

• Oversaw the production of all email campaigns and web graphics, as well as maintained corporate website content, event landing pages, and company Intranet.

#### **Education**

# **Texas State University**

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014